<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="arizona-revised-statutes">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#cosilico">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-az/act/28-2470.24" />
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-az/act/28-2470.24" />
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" />
          <FRBRauthor href="#arizona-legislature" />
          <FRBRcountry value="us-az" />
          <FRBRnumber value="28-2470.24" />
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-az/act/28-2470.24/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-az/act/28-2470.24/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" />
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng" />
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/akn/us-az/act/28-2470.24/eng@2025-12-31/xml" />
          <FRBRuri value="/akn/us-az/act/28-2470.24/eng@2025-12-31/xml" />
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references>
        <TLCOrganization eId="arizona-legislature" href="https://www.azleg.gov" showAs="Arizona State Legislature" />
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico AI" />
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_28_2470_24">
        <num>28-2470.24</num>
        <heading>Neurodiversity services and research special plates; fund</heading>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_a">
          <num>A.</num>
          <content>
            <p>If, by December 31, 2024, a person pays $32,000 to the department for the implementation of this section, the department shall issue neurodiversity services and research special plates. The person that provides the $32,000 shall design the neurodiversity services and research special plates. The design and color of the neurodiversity services and research special plates are subject to the approval of the department. The director may allow a request for neurodiversity services and research special plates to be combined with a request for personalized special plates. If the director allows such a combination, the request shall be in a form prescribed by the director and is subject to the fees for the personalized special plates in addition to the fees required for the neurodiversity services and research special plates.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_b">
          <num>B.</num>
          <content>
            <p>Of the $25 fee required by section 28-2402 for the original special plates and for renewal of special plates, $8 is a special plate administration fee and $17 is an annual donation.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_c">
          <num>C.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The department shall deposit, pursuant to sections 35-146 and 35-147, all special plate administration fees in the state highway fund established by section 28-6991 and shall transmit all donations collected pursuant to this section to the neurodiversity services and research special plate fund established by this section.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_d">
          <num>D.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The neurodiversity services and research special plate fund is established consisting of monies deposited pursuant to this section. The director shall administer the fund. The first $32,000 in the fund shall be reimbursed to the person that paid the implementation fee to the department pursuant to subsection A of this section. Not more than ten percent of the monies deposited in the fund annually shall be used for the cost of administering the fund. Monies in the fund are continuously appropriated.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_e">
          <num>E.</num>
          <content>
            <p>The director shall annually allocate monies from the fund to two entities that are qualified under section 501(c)(3) of the United States internal revenue code for federal income tax purposes and that are engaged with the neurodiversity community as follows:</p>
          </content>
          <paragraph eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_e__subsec_1">
            <num>1.</num>
            <content>
              <p>One entity must:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_e__subsec_1__subsec_a">
              <num>a.</num>
              <content>
                <p>Be an internationally recognized leader that conducts innovative research, provides evidence-based practices, disseminates effective training and builds inclusive communities for individuals of all ages with autism and their families.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_e__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <num>b.</num>
              <content>
                <p>Offer nearly twenty programs and services rooted in applied behavior analysis and provide community outreach and training.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_e__subsec_1__subsec_c">
              <num>c.</num>
              <content>
                <p>Have an innovative research program that brings together scientists and stakeholders to gain a better understanding of possible causes of autism, identify better treatments and educate others about how to improve the quality of life for those impacted.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_e__subsec_2">
            <num>2.</num>
            <content>
              <p>One entity must:</p>
            </content>
            <subparagraph eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_e__subsec_2__subsec_a">
              <num>a.</num>
              <content>
                <p>Advance innovative residential and community options for adults with autism, down syndrome, traumatic brain injury and other neurodiversities through its vision for fueling a new wave of real estate and community integrated living options.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_e__subsec_2__subsec_b">
              <num>b.</num>
              <content>
                <p>Have a property that is eighty-one thousand square feet and that contains a sixty-three unit apartment community set in an urban area.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_e__subsec_2__subsec_c">
              <num>c.</num>
              <content>
                <p>Have an institute that leverages the property described in subdivision (b) of this paragraph to serve as a research and development site and to support the replication of residential and postsecondary education models through collaboration among the public, private, philanthropic and nonprofit sectors.</p>
              </content>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_28_2470_24__subsec_f">
          <num>F.</num>
          <content>
            <p>On notice from the director, the state treasurer shall invest and divest monies in the fund as provided by section 35-313, and monies earned from investment shall be credited to the fund.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>